In love, there are no boundaries.
The English Patient is a drama, romance, war film directed by Anthony Minghella.
In the 1930s, Count Almásy is a Hungarian map maker employed by the Royal Geographical Society to chart
the vast expanses of the Sahara Desert along with several other prominent explorers.
As World War II unfolds, Almásy enters into a world
of love, betrayal, and politics.
Almásy, played by Ralph Fiennes.
Hana, played by Juliette Binoche.
David Caravaggio, played by Willem Dafoe.
Katharine Clifton, played by Kristin Scott Thomas.
Sikh Kip, played by Naveen Andrews.
Geoffrey Clifton, played by Colin Firth.
The English Patient is a 1996 epic romantic war drama film directed by Anthony Minghella from his
own script based on the 1992 novel by Michael Ondaatje, and produced by Saul Zaentz.
The film stars Ralph Fiennes and Kristin Scott Thomas alongside Juliette Binoche,
Willem Dafoe, Naveen Andrews and Colin Firth in supporting roles.
The protagonist of the title, a man burned beyond recognition who speaks with an English accent, recalls his history in a series of
flashbacks, revealing to the audience his true identity and the love affair in which he was involved before the war.
The film ends with an onscreen statement that it is a fictionalized account of
László Almásy (died 1951) and other historical figures and events.
The film received widespread critical acclaim and emerged as a
major commercial success at the box-office.
The film received twelve nominations at the 69th Academy Awards, winning nine, including Best
Picture, Best Director for Minghella, and Best Supporting Actress for Binoche.
It was also the first to receive a Best Editing
Oscar for a digitally edited film.
Ralph Fiennes, playing the titular character, and Kristin Scott
Thomas were Oscar-nominated for their performances.
The film also won five BAFTA Awards and two Golden Globes.
The British Film Institute ranked The English Patient the
55th-greatest British film of the 20th century.
The American Film Institute ranked it the 56th-greatest love story of all time.
The film explores themes of egypt, secret love, amnesia, airplane, cairo.
The tone is emotional.